N. Howell Furman Papers, 1903-1961: Inventory
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
N. Howell Furman Papers
1903-1961
C0426
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
22.5 linear feet 21 record center cartons
Furman, N. Howell (Nathaniel Howell), 1892-1965.
N. Howell Furman (Princeton Class of 1913) was a professor of analytical chemistry at Princeton. His collection consists of scholarly papers, correspondence, miscellaneous material relating to the teaching of chemistry at Princeton.
N. Howell Furman (Princeton Class of 1913) was a professor of analytical chemistry at Princeton.
The collection consists of scholarly papers, correspondence, miscellaneous material relating to the teaching of chemistry at Princeton, and printed matter of Furman (Princeton Class of 1913), professor of analytical chemistry. The collection contains his lecture notes, articles, papers, and notebooks, as well as his professional correspondence. There are files of student papers, laboratory work, notebooks, and undergraduate and Ph.D. general examinations. Also included are reports of chemical analyses, minutes of departmental meetings, records of supplies and equipment, notebooks of students' grades, files regarding the Atomic Energy Commission, and material relating to his interest in polarography. Furman’s "Report of Travel," a typewritten manuscript illustrated with photographs, documents his fellowship-funded trip to European chemical plants and university laboratories in 1927 and 1928; it includes a large copy of Bartholomew’s map of Europe (1925) with Furman’s route shown in red ink. In addition, there is printed material including abstracts of papers and offprints of articles by Furman and others.
This is an unprocessed collection and remains in its original arrangement.
Collection is open for research use.
Please consult with Rare Books and Special Collections about having the collection recalled to Firestone Library for your use. This process normally requires 48-72 hours notice.
The papers were a gift of Mrs. Nathaniel Howell Furman. Furman's "Report of Travel" was a gift of Lisa Hawley in 2014.
U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.; Chemistry, Analytic -- New Jersey -- Princeton -- 20th century.; Nuclear energy -- United States.; Polarograph and polarography.; Chemistry, Analytic -- Qualitative.; Chemistry, Analytic -- Quantitative.; Chemistry, Analytic -- Study and teaching -- New Jersey -- Princeton -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Lecture notes.; Examinations.; Chemists -- New Jersey -- Princeton.; Princeton University -- Faculty.; History of science; Princeton University
- Exams, 1930s - 1950s; 1 box
- Exams, 1930s - 1950s; 1 box
- Exams, 1930s - 1950s; 1 box
- Exams and lecture notes, circa 1933-1946; 1 box
- Lecture notes, circa 1938-1950; 1 box
- Course notes, Chemistry 301 - 302, circa 1937-1956; portion of 1 box
- Notes on chemical equilibrium by Robert M. Pease, student, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Notebooks - experiments, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Research notes, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Lecture notes, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- circa 1918-1946, portion of 1 box
- Class notes and student materials - graduate course in Chemistry, 1941-1955; 1 box
- A.E.C. materials, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Research notebooks from Furman's research team, 1945-1948; portion of 1 box
- Lab records, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Student records, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Research at Princeton, Furman and others, including some work for the Department of Defense, dates not examined; 1 box
- Miscellaneous reports and project data, Princeton University, 1940s; 1 box
  [some DOD research]
- Miscellaneous reports and project data, Princeton University, 1940s; 1 box
- Notes, reports, and publications regarding Polarography, 1947-1949; 1 box
- Publications by others and correspondence regarding Polarography, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Graduate student materials, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Undergraduate gradebooks, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Research notes, experiments, reports, 1940s - 1950s; 1 box
- Research notes: projects by organization/company, 1940s - 1950s; portion of 1 box
- Reports, de-classification bulletins, 1940s - 1950s; portion of 1 box
- Reports, correspondence and submissions by others for "Scott's Standard Methods of Chemistry," 6th edition, which Furman edited, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Research notes and reports - Merck and other chemical / pharmaceutical companies, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Graduate student records, laboratory timesheets, and miscellaneous correspondence, 1940s; 1 box
- Class / student records, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Research notes, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Reviews of award nominees and/or PhD candidates, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
- Class notes, student records, 1940s; 1 box
- PhD propositions, 1950s; portion of 1 box
- Department notebooks, Princeton Department of Chemistry, 1904-1931; portion of 1 box
- Letters of recommendation, 1960s; portion of 1 box
- Fellowship reports, 1920s; portion of 1 box
- "Report of Travel" to Europe, 1927-1928; portion of 1 box
- 32101040811380 (Box 1)
- 32101040811398 (Box 2)
- 32101040811406 (Box 3)
- 32101040811414 (Box 4)
- 32101040811422 (Box 5)
- 32101040811430 (Box 6)
- 32101040811448 (Box 7)
- 32101040811455 (Box 8)
- 32101040811463 (Box 9)
- 32101040811471 (Box 10)
- 32101040811489 (Box 11)
- 32101040811497 (Box 12)
- 32101040811505 (Box 13)
- 32101040811513 (Box 14)
- 32101040811521 (Box 15)
- 32101040811539 (Box 16)
- 32101040811547 (Box 17)
- 32101040811554 (Box 18)
- 32101040811562 (Box 19)
- 32101040811570 (Box 20)
- 32101040811588 (Box 21)